- 稳住，苏鲁 - 我们还在轨道上，长官
- Stay on top of it, Mr. Sulu. - We're holding orbit, sir.
船舵失灵了
The helm is sluggish.
控制电路即将超负荷，舰长
Control circuits threatening to overload, captain.
明白了，轮机长
Understood, engineer.
史波克…
Mr. Spock...
…我们无法躲开这些危险区域
...we can't avoid these areas of turbulence.
再绕几圈轨道，我就能把它们标出来
I believe we'll have them plotted in a few more orbits, captain.
医务人员，快来舰桥
Sickbay, to bridge.
转为人工控制，舰长
Switching to manual, captain.
- 我们还要维持现有轨道吗？ - 史波克？
- Do we maintain this orbit? - Spock?
是的，舰长，从科学角度讲这意义重大
This is of great scientific importance, captain.
事实上，我们现在正在穿越时间
We're actually passing through ripples in time.
- 维持现有轨道 - 好的
- Maintain orbit. - Aye, there.
联系星舰司令部
Open a channel to Starfleet Command.
- 是，长官 - 预防措施，上尉
- Yes, sir. - Precautionary measure, lieutenant.
将上周舰长日志发给司令部
Broadcast to Starfleet Command my past week's log entries,
就从仪表读数异常开始
starting with the unusual readings we had on the instruments
以及那些数据如何带我们来这
and how they led us here.
告诉司令部
Inform Starfleet Command that apparently
这颗星球上的某种东西或者某个人
something or someone down on this planet--
老骨头
Bones.
能让时间产生异变
--can affect changes in time,
造成空间紊乱
causing turbulent waves of space displacement.
心动过速
Some heart flutter.
看来要冒一下险，给他注射点可酌辛
I'd better risk a few drops of cordrazine.
这种药不好把握，你确定？
It's tricky stuff. Are you sure you wanna risk--?
你刚才想教我行医，吉姆？
You were about to make a medical comment, Jim?
谁，我吗，医生？
Who, me, doctor?
我们现已避开大部分时空扭曲，舰长
We're guiding around most of the time ripples now, captain.
很好，史波克？
Good. Mr. Spock?
还剩一块区域未标绘，舰长，就快了
All plotted but one, captain. Coming up on it now.
这块区域似乎扭曲得很厉害
Seems to be fairly heavy displacement.
老骨头！
Bones!
回到各自岗位
Get back to your positions.
- 是皮下注射器，舰长 - 里面装的是可酌辛
- The hypo, captain. - It was set for cordrazine.
- 空了 - 通讯官
- Empty. - Communications,
呼叫紧急医疗小组
emergency medical team.
你们这些杀手！刺客！
Killers! Assassins!
我不会让你们得逞！我会先杀了你们！
I won't let you! I'll kill you first!
我不会让你们得逞！
I won't let you!
你们不会得逞的！你们这些杀人犯！杀手！
You won't get me! Murderers! Killers!
发出安全警报
Security alert.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命和新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢地航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
TLF荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：小青龙马
校对：Nick 喜马拉雅
第一季第二十八集
永恒边境之城
舰长日志，补充记录
Captain's log, supplemental entry.
两滴可酌辛，就能救人一命
Two drops of cordrazine can save a man's life.
而麦考伊医生刚刚却意外地
A hundred times that amount
接受了一百倍剂量的药物
has just accidentally been pumped into Dr. McCoy's body,
他发了狂，并逃离了舰桥
and in a strange wild frenzy, he has fled the ship's bridge.
相邻甲板层都处于警戒
All connecting decks have been placed on alert.
我们不知道他的精神异常会持续多久
We have no way of knowing if the madness is permanent
也无法确定会给麦考伊带来什么后果
or temporary or in what direction it will drive McCoy.
4号到11号甲板层…
Continue alert...
…继续保持警戒
...Decks 4 through 11.
医疗部知道的情况并不比我们多
Medical department knows as little as we do.
有记录显示，此剂量的药物可致重度偏执
In dosages approaching this, there's some record of wild paranoia.
这与文献库的资料一致，舰长
Confirmed by the library record tapes, captain.
患者不能辨认熟人
Subjects failed to recognise acquaintances,
固执地认为自己面临致命危险
became hysterically convinced that they were in mortal danger
并且会拼命逃跑
and were seeking escape at any cost.
这种状态很危险，无论对他自己还是…
Extremely dangerous to himself or to anyone else who might--
- 舰桥，这里是安全部，警报，警报 - 这里是舰桥，请讲
- Bridge, Security. Alert, alert. - Bridge here. Go ahead.
我是054号安保员，长官，传送部主管受伤了
Security 054, sir. We just found the transporter chief injured.
舰长，麦考伊医生自行登陆了这颗星球
Captain, Dr. McCoy has beamed himself down to the planet.
舰长，那时候传送装置的目标
And the transporter at that time, captain,
正对准着时间扭曲的中心
was focused on the centre of the time disturbance.
不论那是什么，麦考伊现正位于其中
So whatever's down there, McCoy is in the heart of it.
组织登陆小队，我们去带他回来，呼叫完毕
Set up a landing party. Let's go get him. Kirk out.
这些废墟一直延伸到地平线
These ruins extend to the horizon.
开始记录
Begin recording.
正在记录，长官
Recording, sir.
这些废墟的历史相当久远
And of considerable age.
接近一万个世纪
On the order of 10,000 centuries old.
分遣队，散开
Detail, fan out.
这是什么，史波克？
What is this thing, Mr. Spock?
似乎在散发着某种能量
Seems to be pulsating with power of some kind.
分析一下
Analysis, please.
- 难以置信，舰长 - 有意思
- Unbelievable, captain. - That's funny.
这个物体正是时间扭曲的原因
This single object is the source of all the time displacement.
- 解释一下 - 我无法解释
- Explain. - I can't.
基于我所拥有的科学知识
For this to do what it does is impossible
我无法对此作出解释
by any science I understand.
现在它仍然在不断发射…
It is operating even now...
…能导致时间扭曲的能量波
...putting out waves and waves of time displacement,
我们在几百万英里外就收到过
which we picked up millions of miles away.
登陆部队呼叫进取号，没有麦考伊医生的踪迹
Landing party to Enterprise. No sign of Dr. McCoy.
搜索继续
Search progressing.
惊人的能量
Incredible power.
不可能是我们所知的机器
It can't be a machine as we understand mechanics.
- 那它到底是什么？ - 是一个问题
- Then what is it? - A question.
在你们的太阳诞生之前
Since before your sun burned hot in space,
在你们的种族诞生之前，我就在等候一个问题了
and before your race was born, I have awaited a question.
- 你是什么？ - 我是永恒的守卫者
- What are you? - I am the Guardian of Forever.
你是机器还是生命？
Are you machine or being?
都是也都不是
I am both and neither.
我既是自己的开始，也是自己的结束
I am my own beginning, my own ending.
我不懂为什么你要用谜语做答案
I see no reason for answers to be couched in riddles.
我已尽力简化答案以便你们理解
I answer as simply as your level of understanding makes possible.
这是一道时间之门，舰长
A time portal, captain.
是一道通向其他时空间的门，如果我没猜错的话
A gateway to other times and dimensions, if I'm correct.
对你们而言，这种理解已经足够了
As correct as possible for you.
显然，你们的科技水平还很原始
Your science knowledge is obviously primitive.
是吗？
Really?
史波克，郁闷吗？
Annoyed, Spock?
看
Behold.
如果你们愿意的话，可以通过这里回到过去
A gateway to your own past, if you wish.
你们这些杀手！
Killers!
我不会让你们抓到我的！我要杀了你们！
Killers! I won't let you get me! I'll kill you first!
我不会让你们…你们这些刺客！杀手！
I won't let you get-- Assassins! Murderers! Killers!
史波克！
Spock!
如果那是可以让我们回到过去的门
If that is a doorway back through time,
我们可不可以把老骨头带回一天前，然后…
could we somehow take Bones back a day in time, then...?
再度经历那次事件
Relive the accident.
不过这次要避免意外发生
This time be certain that the hypo accident is avoided.
但是，门里的时间流逝很快，舰长
Look at the speed with which the centuries are passing, captain.
要精确地穿越到那一天，恐怕…
To step through on precisely the day we wish...
守卫者
Guardian.
你能改变时间流逝的速度吗？
Can you change the speed at which yesterday passes?
我生来就如此，不能改变
I was made to offer the past in this manner. I cannot change.
越过那扇门
Strangely compelling, isn't it?
迷失在另外一个世界
To step through there
奇怪而诱人的想法，不是吗？
and lose oneself in another world.
我真是失策
I am a fool.
在这种速度下我们的三录仪还管用
Our tricorder is capable of recording even at this speed.
我却忘了记录鲜活的历史
I've missed taping centuries of living history,
- 以前从来没人亲眼… - 麦考伊医生！
- which no man before has ever-- - Dr. McCoy!
老骨头，不要！
Bones, no!
- 他去哪了？ - 他穿越到了过去
- Where is he? - He has passed into what was.
舰长，我和星舰失去了联系，刚才还在通话中
Captain, I've lost contact with the ship. I was talking to them,
突然就失灵了，没有静电干扰，没有信号
and suddenly, it went dead. No static, just nothing.
寇克呼叫进取号
Kirk to Enterprise.
史考特？
Scotty?
通讯装置没有问题，长官
Nothing wrong with the communicator, sir.
你们的星舰，你们的起源，所有的一切都消失了
Your vessel, your beginning, all that you knew is gone.
麦考伊…
McCoy...
…改变了历史的轨迹
...has somehow changed history.
我们被困在这了？
You mean we're stranded down here?
没有过去，没有未来
With no past, no future.
舰长，我感到害怕
Captain, I'm frightened.
我们所熟悉的那个地球消失了
Earth's not there, at least not the Earth we know.
我们现在完全孤立无援了
We're totally alone.
舰长日志，星历不复存在
Captain's log, no stardate.
我们已经无法计算时间
For us, time does not exist.
回到了过去的麦考伊
McCoy, back somewhere in the past,
改变了历史进程
has effected a change in the course of time.
地球的历史已经改变，进取号也消失了
All Earth history has been changed. There is no starship Enterprise.
现在我们只有一次机会了
We have only one chance.
我们请求守卫者再现地球的历史
We have asked the Guardian to show us Earth's history again.
史波克和我将回到过去
Spock and I will go back into time ourselves
尝试纠正被麦考伊改变的历史
and attempt to set right whatever it was that McCoy changed.
麦考伊走的时候，我正在记录影像
I was recording images at the time McCoy left.
那个时期你们美国尚未开化
A rather barbaric period in your American history.
我可以大致判断什么时候进去
I believe I can approximate just when to jump.
误差可能在一个月之内
Perhaps within a month of the correct time,
幸运的话一周
a week, if we're fortunate.
我们必须在麦考伊之前到达
Make sure we arrive before McCoy got there.
我们必须阻止他…
It's vital we stop him...
…在他做出改变整个历史的举动之前
...before he does whatever it was that changed all history.
守护者…
Guardian...
- …如果我们成功了—— - 你们就可以平安归来
- ...if we are successful-- - Then you will be returned.
就像你们从未离开过
It will be as though none of you had gone.
舰长，这项任务不太可能完成
Captain, it seems impossible.
即使你们能顺利回到合适的时间
Even if you're able to find the right date--
也不太可能找到麦考伊
Then even finding McCoy would be a miracle.
但我们别无选择
There is no alternative.
史考特…
Scotty...
…如果过了很久我们都没有回来
...when you think you've waited long enough,
每个人都要试一试，即使失败了
each of you will have to try it. Even if you fail,
至少你们也会在过去的某个地方活下来
at least you'll be alive in some past world somewhere.
- 遵命 - 只剩下几秒了，长官，准备
- Aye. - Seconds now, sir. Stand by.
先生们，祝你们好运
Good luck, gentlemen.
至少要好好地活着，长官
Happiness at least, sir.
就是…
And...
…现在！
...now!
我看过这个时期的照片
I've seen old photographs of this period.
- 当时发生了经济危机 - 被称为大萧条时期，大约在1930年
- An economic upheaval had occurred. - It was called Depression, circa 1930.
相当萧条
Quite barbaric.
我们的服饰似乎与这个时代不太相称
We seem to be costumed a little out of step with the time.
恐怕他们会难以接受我的外表
I'm afraid I'm going to be difficult to explain in any case, captain.
嗯，史波克，如果无法伪装，那我们要设法…
Well, Mr. Spock, if we can't disguise you, we'll find some way of...
- 解释 - 那应该很有意思
- ...explaining you. - That should prove interesting.
我们走吧
Let's get out of here.
有意思
Fascinating.
小心点！看好路！
Look out, will you? Why don't you watch where you're going!
要行窃吗，舰长？
Theft, captain?
呃，我们先劫富，完事了…再济贫
Well, we'll steal from the rich and give back to the poor later.
我感觉喜欢上了这个年代，单纯好应付
I think I'm gonna like this century. Simple, easier to manage.
我们解释起来也不会太难…
We're not gonna have any difficulty explaining--
嗯？
Well?
你是个警官，我认得老军装
You're a police officer. I recognise the traditional accoutrements.
你刚才说会很好解释的
You were saying you'll have no trouble explaining it.
我这朋友显然是个中国人
My friend is obviously Chinese.
我想你注意到他的耳朵了，其实是这样
I see you've noticed the ears. They're actually easy to explain.
是我在小时候遭遇的不幸意外
Perhaps the unfortunate accident I had as a child.
小时候遭遇的不幸意外
The unfortunate accident he had as a child.
他的头被卡在一台…
He caught his head in a mechanical...
…碾米机里
...rice picker.
可是，幸运的是附近有个美国传教士
But, fortunately, there was an American missionary living close by
他的主业正好是整形医生
who was actually a skilled plastic surgeon in civilian life--
好吧，好吧！放下装束把手放在墙上
All right, all right! Drop those bundles and put your hands on that wall there.
快点！
Come on!
哦，你妻子太粗心了，让你穿成这样出门
Oh, how careless of your wife to let you go out that way.
- 什么？ - 哦，是的，十分凌乱
- What? - Oh, yes, it's quite untidy.
过来，我帮你
Here, let me help you.
事实上你喜欢我以前的样子
You were actually enjoying my predicament back there.
- 偶尔你看上去像人 - 舰长，作为我的长官
- At times, you seem quite human. - Captain, I hardly believe that insults
你好像无权这样侮辱我
are within your prerogative as my commanding officer.
抱歉
Sorry.
我们遇到了困境
Time we faced the unpleasant facts.
首先，我觉得我们比麦考伊早到一周
First, I believe we have about a week before McCoy arrives,
- 但我们不确定 - 在哪里
- but we can't be certain. - Arrives where,
檀香山，博伊西，圣地亚哥？
Honolulu, Boise, San Diego?
为什么不是外蒙古呢？
Why not Outer Mongolia, for that matter?
这只是理论
There is a theory.
逻辑上讲时间是流动的
There could be some logic to the belief that time is fluid,
就像一流河，有水流和漩涡
like a river with currents, eddies, backwash.
有个漩涡把麦考伊带到某时某地
And the same currents that swept McCoy to a certain time and place
或许也会把我们带到那里
might sweep us there too.
舰长，我们只能希望如此
Unless that is true, captain, we have no hope.
无法得知他到达的确切时间和地点
Frustrating. Locked in here is the exact place and moment of his arrival,
甚至想象他在做什么
even the images of what he did.
除非我能将传感器和星舰电脑连接
If only I could tie this tricorder in with the ship's computers
哪怕就几分钟
for just a few moments.
你能在这制造一台电脑吗？
Couldn't you build some form of computer aid here?
在这个还在使用真空管的年代？
In this zinc-plated, vacuum-tubed culture?
是的，逻辑上讲它很复杂，史波克先生
Yes, well, it would pose an extremely complex problem in logic, Mr. Spock.
对不起，我有时候对你期望太高
Excuse me. I sometimes expect too much of you.
谁在那里？
Who's there?
对不起，小姐，我们冒昧打扰
Excuse us, miss. We didn't mean to trespass.
外面很冷
It's cold outside.
用谎言来打招呼很可怜，外面没那么冷
A lie is a very poor way to say hello. It isn't that cold.
不
No.
我们正被警察追捕
We were being chased by a policeman.
为啥？
Why?
就为这些衣服
These clothes.
偷来的
We stole them.
我们没一点钱
We didn't have any money.
好吧，我可以帮你们一把
Well, I could do with some help around here,
洗盘子，扫地，日常打扫
doing dishes, sweeping, general cleaning.
能给多少钱？
At what rate of payment?
我需要真空电子管，我的爱好
I need radio tubes and so forth. My hobby.
每小时15分，一天10小时
Fifteen cents an hour for ten hours a day.
你们叫什么？
What are your names?
我叫寇克，他是…
Mine is Jim Kirk. His is...
…史波克
...Spock.
我叫伊迪丝·凯乐
I'm Edith Keeler.
好吧，就从打扫这里开始
Well, you can start by cleaning up down here.
对不起，小姐
Excuse me, miss.
我们在哪？
Where are we?
你们在21街传教所
You're in the 21st Street Mission.
你负责这里？
Do you run this place?
是的，寇克先生
Indeed I do, Mr. Kirk.
电子真空管之类
Radio tubes and so on.
我欣赏爱好，史波克先生
I approve of hobbies, Mr. Spock.
晚安
Good evening.
- 你会后悔的 - 为什么？
- You'll be sorry. - Why?
世界上哪有免费午餐？
You expect to eat for free or something?
你得听人说教
You gotta listen to goody two-shoes.
现在，我听到一些流言蜚语
And now, as I'm sure that somebody out there has said,
是时候付汤钱了
it's time to pay for the soup.
她长得倒算不错
Not that she's a bad-looking broad,
但如果她真的想帮助大伙摆脱困境
but if she really wanted to help out a fella in need--
闭嘴，闭嘴
Shut up. Shut up.
我相信她说的
I wanna hear what she has to say.
是的，当然，舰长
Yes, of course, captain.
让我们直说吧
Now, let's start by getting one thing straight.
我不是一个慈善家
I'm not a do-gooder.
如果你好吃懒做，还是个酒鬼
If you're a bum, if you can't break off with the booze
或者其它任何坏习惯
or whatever it is that makes you a bad risk,
那么请离开
then get out.
我不打算告诉你们怎样寻找爱和幸福
Now, I don't pretend to tell you how to find happiness and love
因为你们尚未解决温饱
when every day is just a struggle to survive,
但是我相信你们应该努力生存
but I do insist that you do survive,
因为未来的生活将更美好
because the days and the years ahead are worth living for.
不久的一天…
One day soon...
…人类能够驾驭惊人的能量
...man is going to be able to harness incredible energies...
…甚至是原子
...maybe even the atom.
能把我们送到其他地方
Energies that could ultimately hurl us to other worlds
通过某种宇宙飞船
in some sort of spaceship.
人类到达太空
And the men that reach out into space
有办法养活全世界千百万挨饿的人
will be able to find ways to feed the hungry millions of the world
治愈他们的疾病
and to cure their diseases.
他们将能给每个人以希望
They will be able to find a way to give each man hope
和一个正常的未来
and a common future.
这就是活着的价值
And those are the days worth living for.
沙漠变绿洲…
Our deserts will bloom...
不久的将来发展原子能
Development of atomic power is years away,
之后是太空飞行
space flight years after that.
- 当然，这些不会很快发生 - 天才的洞察力
- Now, it won't happen tomorrow, - Speculation. Gifted insight.
但一定会实现
but it will come.
我觉得她很特别，史波克
I find her most uncommon, Mr. Spock.
为明天而打基础，作好准备不要放弃
Prepare for tomorrow. Get ready. Don't give up.
寇克先生
Mr. Kirk.
你真了不起
You are uncommon workmen.
地下室看上去抛过光了
That basement looks like it's been scrubbed and polished.
然后我们汇报其他工作？
Then we can report back for other work?
是的，早上7点
Yes, 7:00 in the morning.
- 你晚上有地铺睡吗？ - 什么？
- Do you have a flop for the night? - A what?
这方面你是个新人，不是吗？地铺就是睡觉的地方
You really are new at this, aren't you? A flop is a place to sleep.
这里有间空房，2块钱一礼拜
There's a vacant room at the place where I live for $2 a week.
- 如果你需要，我会带你过去 - 谢谢
- If you want to, I'll take you there. - Thank you.
我们有地铺了
We have a flop.
- 我们有啥？舰长 - 睡觉的地方
- We have a what, captain? - A place to sleep.
怎么没人早点说
One might have said so in the first place.
舰长，我得要些铂
Captain, I must have some platinum.
一小块就够了，5或者6磅
A small block would be sufficient, 5 or 6 pounds.
通上电流之后
By passing certain circuits through there
可以用作双励磁铁芯--
to be used as a duo-dynetic field core--
史波克，我给你买了些蔬菜
Mr. Spock, I've brought you some assorted vegetables,
腊肠和硬皮卷归我
bologna and a hard roll for myself,
花了过去3天
and I've spent the other nine-tenths
工资总和的另外九成
of our combined salaries for the last three days
来满足你的这些要求
on filling this order for you.
史波克，这个袋子里没有铂金或者金银
Mr. Spock, this bag does not contain platinum, silver or gold,
短期之内我们也买不起
nor is it likely to in the near future.
舰长，你要我对付的这些设备
Captain, you're asking me to work with equipment
简直就是原始的石刀或兽皮
which is hardly very far ahead of stone knives and bearskins.
麦考伊过几天就要来了
McCoy will be along in a few days,
也许更快
perhaps sooner.
不能保证到时这些电路会把我们凑到一起
There's no guarantee that these currents in time will bring us together.
- 试了才知道 - 舰长…
- This has to work. - Captain...
舰长，按目前速度要三周甚至一个月
Captain, in three weeks at this rate, possibly a month,
我可能在制造最早的存储电路
I might reach the first mnemonic memory circuits.
你的帽子
Your cap.
现在跟我走，有个5个小时的工作
If you can leave right away, I can get you five hours work
每小时22美分
at 22 cents an hour.
什么？那究竟是什么？
What--? What on earth is that?
夫人，我正试图构建初始存储电路
I am endeavouring, ma'am, to construct a mnemonic memory circuit
用石刀和兽皮
using stone knives and bearskins.
舰长
Captain.
干细活的工具
Tools for finely detailed work.
那个盒子用密码锁锁着
That toolbox was locked with a combination lock,
你开的非常专业
and you opened it like a real pro.
为什么那样做？
Why did you do it?
我需要这些精美工具制作无线电设备
I needed the fine tools for my radio work.
天一亮我就还回去
They'd have been returned in the morning.
- 不，对不起，我不能 - 如果史波克
- No, I'm sorry, I can't-- - If Mr. Spock
说他需要这些工具
says that he needs the tools
明天早上得放回来
and that they'd be returned tomorrow morning,
我可以用声誉担保，凯乐小姐
you can bet your reputation on that, Miss Keeler.
有个条件
On one condition.
陪我走回去？
Walk me home?
我还有几个问题正要问你们俩
I still have a few questions I'd like to ask about you two.
不要摆出那种“又来审问我俩”的表情
Oh, and don't give me that "questions-about-little-old-us" look.
我们都知道你们俩和环境格格不入
You know as well as I do how out of place you two are around here.
有趣
Interesting.
你认为我们来自哪里，凯乐小姐？
Where would you estimate we belong, Miss Keeler?
你…
You...
…站在他的立场，好像你一直在他身边
...at his side, as if you've always been there and always will.
而你…
And you...
你来自其他地方
You belong in another place.
我不知道哪里，怎么来的
I don't know where or how.
我要彻底弄明白
I'll figure it out eventually.
我要处理火炉
I'll finish with the furnace.
“舰长”
"Captain."
就算他没开口，似乎都在说那个词
Even when he doesn't say it, he does.
晚安，亲爱的，即使我不在你身边
Good night, sweetheart Though I'm not beside you
晚安，亲爱的，我的爱依旧向着你
Good night, sweetheart Still my love will guide you
为什么史波克叫你舰长？
Why does Spock call you captain?
你们一起打过仗？
Were you in the war together?
我们一起服役
We served together.
你不想讲讲？
And you don't want to talk about it?
为什么？
Why?
你做错了什么？你害怕什么？
Did you do something wrong? Are you afraid of something?
无论怎么样我都会帮你
Whatever it is, let me help.
“我会帮你”
"Let me help."
从现在之后一百年，我相信
A hundred years or so from now, I believe,
一位著名小说家会以此写出一部经典
a famous novelist will write a classic using that theme.
他将推崇这三个字甚至超过“我爱你”
He'll recommend those three words even over "I love you."
几个世纪后？
Centuries from now?
他是谁？他是哪里人？
Who is he? Where does he come from?
他会是哪里人？
Where will he come from?
天真的问题，想要天真的回答吗？
Silly question. Wanna hear a silly answer?
好啊
Yes.
猎户座腰带最左边的恒星，它的其中一颗行星
A planet circling that far left star in Orion's belt. See?
石刀和兽皮怎样了？
How are the stone knives and bearskins?
我大概找到焦点了
I may have found our focal point in time.
我觉得你也应该发现有个地方烧焦了
I think you may also find you have a connection burning someplace.
是的，我使它们过载了
Yes, I'm overloading those lines.
我相信我们在这屏幕上找到答案了，舰长
I believe we'll have our answer on this screen, captain.
- 好 - 可是，舰长…
- Good. - And, captain...
- …你会发现这有些痛苦 - 好吧，让我看看你发现了什么
- ...you may find this a bit distressing. - Well, let's see what you have.
我减慢了时间涡流中的记录
I've slowed down the recording we made from the time vortex.
1936年2月23日，从现在起六年后
February 23, 1936. Six years from now.
“总统和伊迪丝·凯乐…
"The president and Edith Keeler...
…今天某时被授予”
...conferred for some time today--"
- 有多糟？ - 糟透了
- How bad? - Bad enough.
- 总统和伊迪丝·凯乐… - 看上去不太可能，吉姆
- The president and Edith Keeler... - It would seem unlikely, Jim.
刚才，我看了1930年的报纸文章
A few moments ago, I read a 1930 newspaper article.
我们知道她的将来
We know her future.
从现在起6年内她将变的非常重要
Within six years from now, she'll become very important,
- 全国闻名 - 然而，舰长
- nationally famous. - Or, captain,
伊迪丝·凯乐会在这一年死去
Edith Keeler will die this year.
我看到她的讣告
I saw her obituary.
某个交通意外
Some sort of traffic accident.
你一定搞错了
You must be mistaken.
都不是真的
They both can't be true.
舰长，伊迪丝·凯乐是我们要找的焦点
Captain, Edith Keeler is the focal point in time we've been looking for.
就是我们和麦考伊闯入的时间点
The point in time that both we and Dr. McCoy have been drawn to.
她有两种可能的将来
She has two possible futures then.
根据她的生死…
And depending on whether she lives or dies...
…所有的历史都将被改写
...all of history will be changed.
- 而麦考伊… - 是随机因素
- And McCoy... - Is the random element.
那他会做什么？杀了她？
In his condition, what does he do? Does he kill her?
或他阻止她被杀
Or perhaps he prevents her from being killed.
我们不知道是哪种
We don't know which.
修好这东西
Get this thing fixed.
我们必须在麦考伊来之前弄清楚
We must find out before McCoy arrives.
舰长，假设我们发现
Captain, suppose we discover
让事情顺其自然的话，伊迪丝·凯乐必须死
that in order to set things straight again, Edith Keeler must die?
谋杀！杀手！
Assassins! Murderers!
杀手！谋杀！
Murderers! Assassins!
问你，这是什么星球？
You, what planet is this?
不！不要跑！我要杀了你！
No! Don't run! I won't kill you!
他们杀了人！
It's they who do the killing!
不要跑！我要杀了你！
Don't run! I won't kill you!
为什么？为什么人们对登上月球不屑一顾
Why? What is so funny about man reaching for the moon?
- 你是怎么知道的？ - 我就是知道了，仅此而已，我能感觉到
- How do you know? - I just know, that's all. I feel it.
还有，我觉得会有一天他们把
And more, I think that one day they're going to take
花在战争和死亡上的钱
all the money that they spend now on war and death--
都用在拯救生命上
And make them spend it on life.
是啊
Yes.
我们想法一致，语言相通
You see the same things that I do. We speak the same language.
非常一致
The very same.
我很高兴你也逃出来了
I'm glad you got away too.
- 是啊，我… - 为什么你觉得他们要杀我们？
- Yeah, I... - Why do you think they wanna kill us?
看，小伙子，你喝多了
Look, fella, you take a sip too much of that old wood alky,
看上去每件事都像
and almost anything seems like it--
哪里？
Where?
我们在哪里？
Where are we?
地球？
Earth?
星座看上去是的，可是…
The constellations seem right, but...
解释
Explain.
- 解释这一切 - 我…
- Explain this trick. - I...
有两条腿
Biped.
矮小的
Small.
出色的颅骨进化
Good cranial development.
确实是人类血统
No doubt considerable human ancestry.
你是如何伪装这些的？
Is that how you're able to fake all of this?
非常好
Very good.
完美的现代博物馆
Modern museum perfection.
混凝土柱子
Right down to the cement beams.
非常，非常好
Very, very good.
哦，我最好去医院
Oh, I'd give a lot to see the hospital.
大概要缝几针
Probably needles and sutures.
所有的痛苦
All the pain.
以前的医院把人当衣服切开再缝上
Used to had to cut and sew people like garments.
用针缝合
Needles and sutures.
可怕的疼痛
The terrible pain.
我们还有多久得到完整的答案？
How long before we get a full answer?
在我再次尝试前至少需要两天
I'll need at least two more days before I dare make another attempt.
据我们所知麦考伊可能一周前就到了
McCoy could have been in the city a week now for all we know.
他的行为影响她或者改变历史
And whatever he does that affects her and changes history
可能就在今晚或明早
could happen tonight, tomorrow morning.
舰长…
Captain...
…我们捕获的最后一点信息
...our last bit of information was obtained
是以30小时工作和烧掉电路为代价的
at the expense of 30 hours' work in fused and burned circuits.
我必须知道她是生是死，史波克
I must know whether she lives or dies, Spock.
我必须知道该做什么
I must know what to do.
号外！号外！卖报纸啦
Extra! Extra! Get your morning paper!
买张报纸，看看啦
Get your paper. Read all about it!
哦，小姐…
Oh, miss...
…那咖啡，闻起来好香啊
...that coffee, it just smells wonderful.
你气色真难看
You look terrible.
- 你最好坐下，来吧 - 不行，我必须一直走
- You better sit down. Come on. - I can't. I gotta keep moving.
我不能让他们找到我
I can't let them find me.
后屋有张简易床，在那儿他们找不到你，来吧
There's a cot in the backroom. They won't find you there. Come on.
这就是麦考伊改变的历史
This is how history went after McCoy changed it.
这里，30年代后期崛起和平运动
Here, in the late 1 930s, a growing pacifist movement
谁耽误了美国
whose influence delayed the United States' entry
加入二战
into the Second World War.
接着和平谈判被耽搁
While peace negotiations dragged on,
德国就有时间完成重水实验
Germany had time to complete its heavy-water experiments.
德国
Germany.
法西斯，希特勒
Fascism, Hitler.
胜利万岁！胜利万岁！
Sieg Heil! Sieg Heil!
赢得二战
Won the Second World War.
因为所有这一切使他们率先发展原子弹
Because all this lets them develop the A-bomb first.
这没错，舰长，让我再来一遍
There's no mistake, captain. Let me run it again.
伊迪丝·凯乐，和平运动创始人
"Edith Keeler, founder of the peace movement."
她是对的，和平是条明路
But she was right, peace was the way.
她没错，但不是时候
She was right, but at the wrong time.
由于原子弹，和他们的V-2火箭
With the A-bomb, and with their V-2 rockets to carry them,
- 德国称霸整个世界 - 不
- Germany captured the world. - No.
所有这些都是因为麦考伊
And all this because McCoy came back
以某种方式让她死于街头意外
and somehow kept her from dying in a street accident
就如原先那样
as she was meant to.
我们必须阻止他，吉姆
We must stop him, Jim.
她是怎么死的？
How did she die?
在哪一天？
What day?
我只能通过图像估计常规事件
I can estimate general happenings from these images,
但是我不能追溯准确的时间和行动，舰长
but I can't trace down precise actions at exact moments, captain.
对不起
I'm sorry.
史波克…
Spock...
…我觉得
...I believe...
…我爱上伊迪丝·凯乐了
...I'm in love with Edith Keeler.
吉姆，伊迪丝·凯乐必须死
Jim, Edith Keeler must die.
来吧，你现在还没完全好
Hey, now, come on. You're not ready to take on any tigers just yet.
躺下
Lie down.
往常我都会问，“我在哪？”
The most common question to ask would be, "Where am I?"
现在不想问了
I don't think I'll ask it.
- 为什么呢？ - 唯一的回答
- Why not? - The only possible answer
最终都会发现我是…
would conclusively prove that I'm...
…要么无意识或者神经病
...either unconscious or demented.
这里看上去像大约1920或25年的地球
This looks like old Earth around 1920 or '25.
你不介意是30年代吧？
Would you care to try for '30?
我是失去意识的神经病
I am unconscious or demented.
我有一个和你一样谈论地球的朋友
I have a friend that talks about Earth the same way that you do.
- 你想见他吗？ - 我是外科大夫，不是精神病大夫
- Would you like to meet him? - I'm a surgeon, not a psychiatrist.
我是伦纳德·麦考伊
I am Leonard McCoy,
联邦星舰进取号上的高级医务官
senior medical officer aboard the USs Enterprise.
我不是不相信你，只是这不像海军服
I don't mean to disbelieve you, but that's hardly a Navy uniform.
对极了，对极了，亲爱的…
That's quite all right. That's quite all right, dear...
…因为我也不信你
...because I don't believe in you either.
休息会
Get some rest.
伊迪丝
Edith.
- 你在跟踪我吗？先生 - 还是别有用心地
- Are you following me, sir? - With ulterior motives.
这总满意了吧
Would that please you?
我希望意味着什么--
I hope it means what--
我真笨！这楼梯我走了上千次
Stupid! I've been up and down those stairs a thousand times.
要不是你我可能已经摔破膝盖了
I could have broken my neck.
舰长，我无意偷听
Captain, I did not plan to eavesdrop.
不，你当然不是
No, of course you didn't.
我不得不指出当她绊倒…
I must point out that when she stumbled...
如果你不抓住她她可能已经死了
...she might have died right there had you not caught her.
还没到时候，麦考伊不在这里
It's not yet time. McCoy isn't here.
我们对事实不太确定
We're not that sure of our facts.
谁知道何时才是确切的时候？
Who's to say when the exact time will come?
救她，响应你内心的号召
Save her, do as your heart tells you to do,
然而数百万无辜的人将死去
and millions will die who did not die before.
进来
Come in.
- 哇，你看上去气色真好，大夫 - 谢谢
- Well, you look just fine, doctor. - Thank you.
我想你可能想看晚报
I thought you might like to see the evening paper.
不，不一定
No, not particularly.
我相信自己是因强心剂产生了幻觉
You know, I've convinced myself that this is all in a cordrazine hallucination.
- 但我觉得你不是幻觉 - 这就好
- But I've decided you're not. - That's reassuring.
但如果你不是，你是谁？
But if you're not, what are you?
朋友
A friend.
当你出现时，看得出你需要朋友
When you showed up here, you looked like you could use one.
不，我并不是怀疑这个
No, I don't doubt it.
这是哪里，你是负责人？
What about this place, you run it?
我尽力经营
I try to.
- 为什么？ - 必须的
- Why? - It's necessary.
好吧，至少对于我来说
Well, it was for me, at least.
你救了我
You may have saved my life.
通常很多人都会吃错药
Lots of people drink from the wrong bottle sometimes.
他们不会错到我这种程度
Not as wrong as the bottle I drank from.
请允许我表达感激之情，也许这里
Allow me to show my gratitude. Perhaps there's something
我可以做些什么报答你
I can do around here to thank you.
这个待会谈，我要走了
We can talk about that later. I have to go.
我朋友要带我去看克拉克·盖博的电影
My young man is taking me to a Clark Gable movie.
- 谁的电影？ - 克拉克·盖博
- A who movie? - A Clark Gab--
- 难道你不知道？ - 好吧，我知道是什么电影，但是…
- Don't you know? - Well, I know what a movie is, but...
非常奇怪
That's very strange.
你休息会，回头见
You get some rest. I'll see you later.
动作快点，我们能赶上奥芬剧院克拉克·盖博的电影
If we hurry, maybe we can catch the Clark Gable movie at the Orpheum.
- 什么？ - 我就是喜欢看
- What? - I'd just love to see it.
知道吗，麦考伊大夫也这么说
You know, Dr. McCoy said the same--
麦考伊！
McCoy!
伦纳德·麦考伊？
Leonard McCoy?
- 是的，他有任务，他是 - 待在这里
- Yes. He's in the mission. He's-- - Stay right here.
史波克！待在那里！
Spock! Stay right there!
- 这是什么？ - 麦考伊，他就在…
- What is it? - McCoy, he's in--
- 老骨头！老骨头！ - 吉姆！
- Bones! Bones! - Jim!
- 不，吉姆！ - 伊迪丝
- No, Jim! - Edith.
你故意阻止我的，吉姆
You deliberately stopped me, Jim.
我本可以救她，你知道你刚才做了什么？
I could have saved her. Do you know what you just did?
他知道的，医生
He knows, doctor.
他知道的
He knows.
发生了什么，长官？你只是刚离开
What happened, sir? You only left a moment ago.
我们成功了
We were successful.
时间继续流转，一切照旧
Time has resumed its shape. All is as it was before.
许多这样的旅行是可行的，我的大门为你们敞开
Many such journeys are possible. Let me be your gateway.
舰长，进取号已经就绪，他们问我们是否返回
Captain, the Enterprise is up there. They're asking if we wanna beam up.
让我们离开这鬼地方
Let's get the hell out of here.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/